DOCTOR CHA
차 박사
ALL CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS, EVENTS, AND LOCATIONS IN THIS SHOW ARE FICTITIOUS
모든 캐릭터, 조직, 이벤트, 이 쇼의 위치는 허구입니다.
BEAUTIFUL DERMATOLOGY
아름다운 피부과
Hello.
안녕하세요.
DIRECTOR
감독
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
-Good morning. -At this rate, you might put it on me.
-좋은 아침이에요. -이대로라면 나한테 질 수도 있겠네요.
Coats these days look so refined.
요즘 코트가 참 세련되보이네요.
-What color is this? -Give that to me. I'll wear it myself.
-이게 무슨 색이에요? -그거 나한테 줘 제가 직접 입어보겠습니다.
Goodness, I'll put it on for you.
맙소사, 내가 그걸 입혀줄게.
Gosh, jeez.
이런, 이런.
Filming finished late, so I barely made it here on time.
촬영이 늦게 끝났고, 그래서 시간에 맞춰 여기에 간신히 도착했어요.
Gosh, you're so cool.
맙소사, 정말 멋지군요.
You go to broadcasting stations and get filmed.
방송국에 가면 그리고 촬영을 받으세요.
Why are you all dressed up?
왜 다들 옷을 입고 있어요?
Are you going on a blind date or something?
소개팅 가시나요? 아니면 뭔가?
I use days like this as an excuse to dress up.
나는 이런 날을 사용한다 차려입기 위한 핑계로.
How do you like it? It's brand new.
어때요? 그것은 아주 새로운 것입니다.
Regardless, the face is what completes a look.
아무리봐도 얼굴이네 룩을 완성하는 것.
What happened to your face?
얼굴에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
What do you mean? I really worked hard on my makeup today.
무슨 뜻이에요? 오늘 메이크업 정말 열심히 했어요.
Let's go. Let's drink coffee.
갑시다. 커피를 마시자.
Jeez, that cold-hearted woman.
이런, 그 냉정한 여자.
I look pretty.
나는 예뻐 보인다.
Gosh.
이런.
My friend, I keep telling you to come to get treatments before it gets worse.
친구야 내가 계속 오라고 하는데 더 심해지기 전에 치료를 받으려면
Why won't you listen?
왜 듣지 않니?
It doesn't look good to get free treatments for being a friend.
안 좋아 보이는데 친구가 되어주면 무료로 치료를 받을 수 있어요.
Then you can just pay for it.
그러면 비용을 지불하시면 됩니다.
Your mother-in-law is over 70,
시어머니가 70이 넘으셨고,
and she comes here more often than to the grocery store.
그리고 그 사람이 여기 와요 식료품점에 가는 것보다 더 자주요.
Hey, my mother-in-law has always lived that kind of lifestyle.
안녕, 우리 시어머니 항상 그런 생활 방식을 살아왔습니다.
Hey, do I look that awful?
야, 내가 그렇게 이상해 보여?
Yes. Are you not eating well?
예. 밥을 잘 못 먹나요?
I mean, your face seems yellowish.
내 말은, 네 얼굴이 누렇게 보인다는 거야.
-What? -And your eyes look a little jaundiced.
-무엇? - 그리고 눈이 좀 황달이 있는 것 같아요.
What?
무엇?
I'm just tired.
그냥 피곤해요.
I haven't been feeling well the past few days.
기분이 좋지 않았어 지난 며칠.
Jeez.
이런.
Hey, that's that. Do you have any good news these days?
이봐, 그게 바로 그거야. 요즘 좋은 소식이 있나요?
-What good news? -You have everything
- 무슨 좋은 소식이요? -당신은 모든 것을 가지고 있습니다
but marriage.
하지만 결혼.
Marriage, my foot. That's so ridiculous.
결혼, 내 발. 정말 말도 안 돼요.
-Stop trying to be funny. -You'll be a virgin forever at this rate.
- 웃기려고 노력하지 마세요. -이대로라면 영원히 처녀가 될 거야.
Honestly, on that subject, aren't you purer than me?
솔직히 그 주제에 관해서는 당신은 나보다 더 순수하지 않나요?
It's been over ten years
10년이 넘었어요
since you and your husband started sleeping in separate rooms.
당신과 당신의 남편 이후로 별도의 방에서 자기 시작했습니다.
Doesn't that practically make you a born-again virgin?
그게 실제로 당신을 만들지 않습니까? 거듭난 처녀?
You little…
너 좀…
Listen, the love between a married couple
들어봐, 부부의 사랑
isn't always maintained through physical aspects.
항상 유지되지는 않습니다 신체적 측면을 통해.
It's a world of complexities and subtleties
복잡한 세상이군요 그리고 미묘함
that a spinster like you wouldn't know about.
너 같은 노처녀야 대해 알지 못할 것입니다.
Fine, you can spend the rest of your life
좋아, 남은 인생을 보내도 돼
having your heart flutter at even the sight of your husband.
설레는 마음을 갖고 남편이 보는 앞에서도요.
You'll be like that little girl Candy from that romantic series.
넌 저 어린 소녀 캔디처럼 될 거야 그 로맨틱 시리즈에서요.
Hey, let's tackle those freckles first.
먼저 주근깨부터 해결해 볼까요?
You're such a mess. It's hard to know where to start.
당신은 정말 엉망입니다. 어디서부터 시작해야 할지 알기가 어렵습니다.
Let's go, Ms. Cha Candy.
가자, 차 캔디 씨.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Most people throw a fit because they couldn't become a doctor,
대부분의 사람들은 발작을 일으킨다. 의사가 될 수 없었기 때문이다.
so why did you choose to become a full-time housewife?
그럼 왜 선택했어요? 전업 주부가 되려면?
Don't you think it's a waste of your medical license? I'm done.
낭비라고 생각하지 않니? 당신의 의사 면허증? 난 끝났어.
I don't think it's a waste at all.
전혀 낭비라고 생각하지 않습니다.
While you were diligently looking after your patients and starting this clinic,
네가 열심히 돌봐주는 동안 당신의 환자들과 이 진료소를 시작하는 것,
do you think I was just relaxing at home?
내가 그냥 집에서 쉬고 있었던 것 같아?
I gave birth to two kids and raised them into proper human beings.
아이 둘을 낳고 키웠어요 올바른 인간으로.
You've worked hard to study medicine
의학 공부하느라 고생하셨어요
and used it to work to create a great life for yourself.
그리고 그것을 일에 사용했습니다 스스로 멋진 삶을 창조하는 것.
But isn't raising two human beings like I did
그런데 안 키워요 나처럼 두 사람이
future-oriented and a contribution to the development of this country?
미래 지향적이며 공헌 이 나라의 발전을 위해?
Candy's leaving.
캔디가 떠난다.
Hey, are you mad?
야, 너 화났어?
-I'm fine. -You are mad. Jeong-suk…
-잘 지내요. -당신은 미쳤어요. 정숙…
AWARD FOR ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENT BAEK MI-HEE
학업 성취에 대한 상 백미희
LETTER OF APPOINTMENT
임명장
EPISODE 1
에피소드 1
PLASTIC SURGERY CLINIC, CLINIC
성형외과, 클리닉
Most people throw a fit because they couldn't become a doctor,
대부분의 사람들이 발작을 일으킵니다. 왜냐하면 그들은 의사가 될 수 없었기 때문입니다.
so why did you choose to become a full-time housewife?
그런데 왜 선택하셨나요? 전업 주부가 되려면?
Don't you think it's a waste of your medical license?
그렇지 않나요? 의사 면허증이 낭비인가요?
Goodness. Young man, are you okay?
맙소사. 젊은이, 괜찮아?
Try to breathe. Someone help!
숨을 쉬어보십시오. 누군가 도와주세요!
Someone help! Is there a doctor here?
누군가 도와주세요! 여기 의사가 있나요?
Are there no doctors here?
여기 의사는 없나요?
There's no doctor?
의사는 없나요?
I'm a doctor…
나는 의사입니다…
Here! This person said she's a doctor!
여기! 이 사람은 의사라고 했어요!
There's a doctor!
의사가 있어요!
-Save him. -No.
- 그를 구해주세요. -아니요.
What I meant was…
내 말은…
Gosh.
이런.
Give me this. Lift your head.
이것을 주세요. 머리를 들어보세요.
Sir, hang in there.
선생님, 거기 좀 참으세요.
Intubation.
삽관.
Call 911!
911에 전화하세요!
Come on, wake up, sir!
자, 일어나세요 선생님!
We need an ambulance!
구급차가 필요해요!
Driver, stop!
운전기사님, 멈춰요!
We're going to transfer him to a nearby hospital.
우리는 그를 옮길 예정이다 근처 병원으로.
You may not be his guardian,
당신은 그의 보호자가 아닐 수도 있습니다.
but we heard you're a doctor. Could you come with us?
하지만 당신이 의사라고 들었습니다. 우리와 함께 갈 수 있나요?
Isn't that lady a little weird?
저 아줌마 좀 이상하지 않아?
Right? She said she was a doctor,
오른쪽? 그녀는 의사라고 하더군요,
but did you see her hands tremble in front of the guy?
그런데 그 사람 손이 떨리는 걸 봤어? 그 사람 앞에서?
We have to get going quickly.
우리는 빨리 가야 해요.
Yes, I'll go.
응, 갈게.
SEOMYEONG UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL DOCTOR ROY KIM
서면대학교병원 로이킴 박사
I'm a surgeon. I'll go with you too.
나는 외과 의사입니다. 나도 같이 갈게.
The LMA won't go in because of his swollen airway.
LMA가 들어가지 않아요 그의 기도가 부어오르기 때문이다.
What should we do?
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Please help me. What should we do?
도와주세요. 우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Doctor.
의사.
Step aside.
물러나세요.
Sir.
선생님.
He has a pulse. We need to do a tracheotomy.
그는 맥박이 있습니다. 기관절개술을 해야 해요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Please give me an antiseptic.
방부제를 주세요.
Bag, please.
가방 주세요.
Sir, are you awake?
선생님, 일어났어요?
If you can hear my voice, please move your hand.
내 목소리가 들리면, 손을 움직여 주세요.
My goodness, Doctor! It worked!
맙소사, 박사님! 효과가 있었어요!
God, thank you so much! You did so great, Doctor!
하느님, 정말 감사합니다! 정말 잘했어요, 박사님!
EMERGENCY MEDICAL CENTER
응급 의료 센터
Excuse me, but what line of work are you in?
실례합니다. 그런데 당신은 어떤 직종에 종사하고 있나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I heard you said you were a doctor.
당신이 의사라고 들었습니다.
Yes.
예.
You shouldn't do that.
그렇게 해서는 안 됩니다.
It's illegal for non-medical personnel to practice medicine.
의료인이 아닌 사람에게는 불법입니다. 의학을 실천하기 위해.
Well,
글쎄,
I know you may not believe this,
나는 당신이 이것을 믿지 않을 수도 있다는 것을 압니다.
but I am a doctor.
하지만 나는 의사입니다.
The thing is, I haven't practiced for over 20 years,
문제는, 20년 넘게 연습을 안 했는데,
so my mind went blank when I came upon that situation.
그래서 내 마음은 텅 비었어 내가 그런 상황에 직면했을 때.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Today is such a great day
오늘은 정말 좋은 날이에요
since that patient met you.
그 환자가 당신을 만난 이후로요.
You were really impressive.
정말 인상적이셨어요.
Then I'll get going first.
그럼 나 먼저 가볼게.
What's the topic for this week's conference?
주제가 무엇인가요? 이번주 회의 때문에?
It's robotic surgery for low rectal cancer.
로봇수술이다 낮은 직장암의 경우.
Professor, what should we do for the patient, Na Tae-gyeong?
교수님, 우리는 어떻게 해야 할까요? 환자 나태경씨를 위해서요?
Monitor the Hemovac
Hemovac 모니터링
and ask the psychiatric department about his depression.
그리고 정신과에 물어보세요 그의 우울증에 대해.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Professor, for tomorrow's conference,
교수님, 내일 회의를 위해
should the first case be Jeon Sang-hyeok?
첫 번째 사건은 전상혁이어야 하나?
No, put Kim Jae-hui's surgery as the first case.
아니 김재희 수술을 넣어라 첫 번째 경우처럼.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
-You can go first. -Okay.
- 먼저 가셔도 돼요. -좋아요.
I get shocked every time I see Jung-min
정민 볼때마다 충격
because he looks so much like you when you were young.
왜냐면 그 사람이 너랑 너무 닮았거든 당신이 어렸을 때.
I think I looked better, no?
내 생각엔 내가 더 좋아 보이는 것 같은데, 그렇지?
I think we should be more discreet.
나는 우리가 좀 더 신중해야 한다고 생각한다.
It'll be bad if your son finds out, don't you think?
아들이 알면 속상할 것 같아요 그렇지 않은 것 같나요?
-Should we have dinner together? -I can't. I have plans.
-저녁 같이 먹을까? - 할 수 없어요. 나에겐 계획이 있다.
-What kind of plans? -Why? Do you think it's a date with a man?
- 어떤 계획이 있나요? -왜? 남자와의 데이트인 것 같나요?
-I'm not going to tell you. -Fine.
-나는 당신에게 말하지 않을 것입니다. -괜찮은.
I'll go now.
나는 지금 갈 것이다.
ALARM, GANGNAM SEMINAR 7:00 P.M.
알람, 강남 세미나 오후 7시
Come on, wake up, sir!
자, 일어나세요 선생님!
We need an ambulance!
구급차가 필요해요!
Excuse me, but what line of work are you in?
실례합니다. 그런데 당신은 어떤 직종에 종사하고 있나요?
-Sorry? -I heard you said you were a doctor.
-죄송합니다? - 의사라고 들었습니다.
-Yes. -You shouldn't do that.
-예. -그러시면 안됩니다.
It's illegal for non-medical personnel to practice medicine.
의료인이 아닌 사람에게는 불법입니다. 의학을 실천하기 위해.
Mother, are you getting back from exercising?
어머니, 돌아오시나요? 운동해서?
-Yes. You must have just gotten back too. -Yes.
-예. 당신도 방금 돌아왔나 봐요. -예.
-Will you make me a glass of detox juice? -Sure.
- 디톡스 주스 한 잔 만들어 주실래요? -확신하는.
I made some earlier and put it in the fridge. I'll get you a glass.
미리 만들어서 넣어두었어요 냉장고에. 내가 한 잔 가져다줄게.
Jeez, the key to juice is its freshness. You have to make it fresh on the spot.
이런, 주스의 핵심은 신선함이에요. 그 자리에서 신선하게 만들어야 해요.
I'm sorry, Mother.
죄송해요, 어머니.
I made it in advance because I had to go out today.
미리 만들어 두었어요 오늘은 나가야 했기 때문에.
Could you drink it just for today?
오늘만 마셔도 될까요?
-By the way, Mother. -What?
-그런데, 어머니. -무엇?
Thank you for lending me your clothes and bag today.
빌려주셔서 감사해요 오늘 네 옷과 가방.
-I'll dry-clean the clothes. -Sure.
-옷은 드라이클리닝할게요. -확신하는.
I have dinner plans tonight, so don't worry about making dinner for me.
오늘 저녁 약속이 있어서, 그러니 나를 위해 저녁을 준비하는 일은 걱정하지 마세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Is Director Baek doing well?
백 감독은 잘 지내나?
Very well.
아주 좋습니다.
-Mother, she treated my freckles today. -That's good.
- 어머니, 오늘 제 주근깨를 치료해 주셨어요. -좋아요.
The new clinic is two times bigger than the last one,
새 병원은 두 배 더 커졌습니다. 지난번보다,
and the interior was designed incredibly well.
그리고 인테리어 엄청나게 잘 디자인되었습니다.
So were you incredibly jealous?
그래서 질투심이 많았나요?
Of course, I was jealous. She even appears on TV.
물론 질투가 났어요. 심지어 TV에도 출연한다.
She's so impressive.
그녀는 정말 인상적이에요.
Even if a woman is skilled and attains fame and prestige,
여자가 실력이 있어도 명성과 위신을 얻게 되며,
it means nothing if she doesn't have a healthy family.
그건 아무 의미도 없어 그녀에게 건강한 가족이 없다면.
Dr. Baek goes on a vacation abroad every season, right?
백박사님 휴가 가세요 해외에서는 매 시즌마다 그렇죠?
But how can you call that a vacation? She has no husband and no kids.
그런데 어떻게 그걸 휴가라고 부를 수 있겠어요? 그녀에게는 남편도 없고 아이도 없습니다.
She rides on planes and wanders around the world because she's empty inside.
그녀는 비행기를 타고 여기저기 돌아다닌다 세상은 속이 텅 비어 있기 때문이다.
To put it nicely, she's a successful career woman,
좋게 말하면, 그녀는 성공한 커리어 우먼이에요.
but just wait ten years.
하지만 10년만 기다리세요.
She'll look sad and pitiful.
그녀는 슬프고 불쌍해 보일 것이다.
You're a hundred times better off. You have a son and a daughter.
당신은 백배 나아졌습니다. 당신에게는 아들과 딸이 있습니다.
Why are you jealous of her? Goodness.
왜 그녀를 질투합니까? 선량.
Rice cooking will now begin.
이제 밥 짓기가 시작됩니다.
-Mom. -Welcome home.
-엄마. - 집에 오신 것을 환영합니다.
You must be tired.
피곤하겠네요.
You didn't even send the fees for my art academy?
수수료도 안 보내주셨네요 내 미술학원을 위해서?
-Right. -The teacher was pressuring me for them.
-오른쪽. - 선생님이 나한테 압력을 가하셨어요.
Oh, no. I'm sorry.
안 돼. 죄송합니다.
I forgot because I was all out of sorts today.
잊어버렸어 왜냐면 오늘은 정말 정신이 없었어요.
-Tomorrow's the competition, right? -Yes.
-내일 대회죠? -예.
If I win an award this time,
이번에 상을 받으면
I can apply for Hanguk and Hongin University.
한국어를 신청할 수 있어요 그리고 홍인대학교.
Goodness, really?
맙소사, 정말요?
I'm home.
나는 집에있다.
You're home late.
당신은 집에 늦게 도착했습니다.
Yes, Father.
네, 아버지.
Welcome home. Jung-min, hurry up and come here.
집에 오신 것을 환영합니다. 정민아, 빨리 이리로 와라.
Okay.
좋아요.
I-rang, when is your next mock exam?
아이랑 다음 모의고사는 언제야?
It's next Tuesday.
다음 주 화요일이에요.
To get into a med school,
의과대학에 진학하려면,
you need to be at least in the top 500 in Korea.
당신은 최소한이어야합니다 한국 500위 안에 들었습니다.
-Okay. -Gosh.
-좋아요. -맙소사.
Mom, you're doing this all by yourself? You're going to work yourself sick.
엄마, 이 모든 일을 혼자 하시나요? 당신은 아프게 일하게 될 것입니다.
It's okay. I can get it done.
괜찮아요. 나는 그것을 끝낼 수 있다.
You should've taken off the doors during the day.
문을 떼어냈어야지 낮에는.
I couldn't sleep because of the drilling.
드릴 작업 때문에 잠을 못 잤습니다.
Sorry. I'll finish it up today.
죄송합니다. 오늘은 이만 마치겠습니다.
This looks good.
좋아 보인다.
Let's eat.
먹자.
Jung-min.
정민.
Yes, Father.
네, 아버지.
Doctors have to deal with people.
의사는 사람을 상대해야 합니다.
I know being an intern is hard, but always maintain a neat look.
인턴이 힘든건 알지만 하지만 항상 깔끔한 모습을 유지하세요.
That's part of being professional.
그것은 전문적인 부분입니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Have you decided on your specialty?
전공을 결정하셨나요?
Yes, it's surgery, of course.
네, 물론 수술이죠.
You still have a lot of time. Think it over before you decide.
아직 시간이 많이 있어요. 결정하기 전에 생각해 보세요.
No, that way of talking just makes the kids soft.
아니, 그런 얘기야 그냥 아이들을 부드럽게 만들어요.
People can be a little soft, and they can be strong too.
사람이 좀 부드러워질 수도 있지만 그리고 그들도 강할 수 있어요.
They can't all be the same. Eat up.
모두가 같을 수는 없습니다. 먹어라.
Only other people's kids can be soft.
다른 사람의 아이들만이 부드러워질 수 있다.
They say that you should treat your kids like you would treat others.
치료를 받아야 한다고 하더군요 당신이 다른 사람을 대하는 것처럼 당신의 아이들도.
-Why is the soup like this? -What?
-국물이 왜 이래요? -무엇?
Why does it taste like this? Oh, no.
왜 이런 맛이 나는 걸까요? 안 돼.
I forgot to put any salt in it.
소금을 넣는 걸 깜빡했어요.
I'll hurry up and season it. Sorry.
서둘러서 양념을 할게요. 죄송합니다.
Where has your mind wandered off to? Are you already getting old?
당신의 마음은 어디로 향하고 있나요? 벌써 늙어가고 있나요?
I guess I am.
그런 것 같아요.
Did you change the coffee beans? The taste was weird.
커피콩을 바꿨나요? 맛이 이상했어요.
Why? I thought it was good.
왜? 나는 그것이 좋다고 생각했다.
I mean, there's a thing called preference. Not everything can be nice and tasty.
즉, 선호도라는 것이 있습니다. 모든 것이 맛있고 맛있을 수는 없습니다.
Okay, I'll buy a whole bunch of the coffee beans you like.
알았어, 한 묶음 사줄게 당신이 좋아하는 커피 원두.
Assemblyman, please get home safely.
의원님, 집에 안전하게 돌아가시기 바랍니다.
Would you like to go in now?
지금 들어가시겠어요?
It's very strange, isn't it?
정말 이상하지 않나요?
Though the times have changed,
시대가 변했지만,
women with a lot of talent and abilities strangely have no luck with men.
재능과 능력이 뛰어난 여성 이상하게 남자들한테는 운이 없어요.
Is that what I'm like?
내가 그런 걸까?
If you were born a man,
남자로 태어났다면,
your talent would have been great enough to take you to the very top.
당신의 재능은 충분히 훌륭했을 것입니다 당신을 가장 높은 곳으로 데려가려고요.
But unfortunately, you were born a woman.
하지만 안타깝게도 당신은 여자로 태어났습니다.
I'm sorry, but you have the fortune of a mistress.
미안하지만 당신은 여주인의 행운.
Marriage has no meaning for people with this kind of fate.
결혼은 의미가 없어요 이런 운명을 가진 사람들을 위해.
It's a shame this fate never lets you go.
이 운명이 당신을 결코 놓아주지 않는다는 것은 부끄러운 일입니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Do you really have to live with that person?
정말로 가지고 있나요? 그 사람이랑 같이 살까?
I want to show them, you see.
나는 그들에게 보여주고 싶다.
People may say it's such a waste for me to cling to a married man.
사람들은 나한테는 너무 아깝다고 할지도 몰라 유부남에게 매달리는 것.
But being this foolish and immature is what makes us human, is it not?
하지만 이렇게 어리석고 철없어서 우리를 인간으로 만드는 것이 바로 그것이지 않습니까?
Since you've waited this long,
그동안 기다려주신 만큼,
let's wait a bit more.
좀 더 기다려 보자.
A single opportunity may come.
단 한번의 기회가 올 수도 있습니다.
And it will come soon.
그리고 그것은 곧 올 것입니다.
I know you don't wear sunglasses because they bother you.
당신이 선글라스를 안 쓴다는 걸 알아요 왜냐하면 그들이 당신을 괴롭히기 때문입니다.
But the sun is really strong in Europe, so you have to wear them.
그런데 유럽은 햇빛이 정말 강해요. 그러니 꼭 입어야 해요.
-Okay? -Okay.
-좋아요? -좋아요.
But these are so old.
하지만 이것들은 너무 오래되었습니다.
You need a new pair.
새 쌍이 필요합니다.
-Honey. -What is it?
-꿀. -이게 뭐죠?
How about sleeping…
자면 어때요…
in the main bedroom from now on?
이제부터 안방에서?
You slept in this room when you'd come home late after surgery,
당신은 이 방에서 잤어요 수술하고 늦게 집에 왔을 때,
but that just turned into us sleeping in separate rooms.
그런데 그게 우리로 변한 거야 별도의 방에서 자고 있습니다.
It's not like we don't have needs.
우리에게 필요가 없는 것은 아닙니다.
So sleeping in separate rooms when we're still young doesn't seem right.
그래서 따로 방에서 자고 우리가 아직 젊을 때는 옳지 않은 것 같아요.
Jeez, that's a bit too out of the blue.
이런, 그건 좀 너무 갑작스러운 일이군요.
Is it?
그렇습니까?
This is too abrupt.
너무 갑작스럽습니다.
Right, I got my freckles treated today. At Mi-hee's clinic.
응, 오늘 주근깨 치료를 받았어. 미희클리닉에서.
-My face is still red, right? Look. -It's really red.
- 아직도 얼굴이 빨개지죠? 바라보다. - 정말 빨개요.
I feel so lethargic these days.
요즘 너무 무기력해요.
It feels like chronic fatigue.
만성피로를 느끼는 것 같습니다.
Then lay down for a bit.
그런 다음 잠시 누워보세요.
Even a dog would laugh if it heard someone as lucky as you
개라도 웃을텐데 당신처럼 운이 좋은 사람이 있다는 소식을 들었다면
say they have chronic fatigue.
만성피로가 있다고 하더군요.
It's menopause. Start working out.
폐경기입니다. 운동을 시작하세요.
Would it kill you to speak nicely to me?
나한테 좋게 얘기하면 죽을 것 같아?
I'm just telling you the facts.
나는 단지 사실을 말하고 있을 뿐입니다.
I don't care whether you wear sunglasses or not.
난 상관없어 선글라스를 쓰든 안 쓰든.
They're your eyes, not mine.
그것은 내 눈이 아니라 당신의 눈입니다.
This style is very popular this season.
이번 시즌에는 이 스타일이 매우 인기가 있습니다.
I'm looking for a pair for my husband.
저는 남편을 위한 한 켤레를 찾고 있어요.
I see. In that case, please wait one moment.
알겠어요. 그 경우, 잠시만 기다려주세요.
What do you think of these?
이것들에 대해 어떻게 생각하세요?
Middle-aged men prefer this kind of style a lot.
중년 남성 이런 스타일을 많이 선호해요.
-They're nice. I'll take these. -Okay.
- 착해요. 내가 가져갈게. -좋아요.
Here you go.
여기요.
Excuse me, ma'am. Are you okay?
죄송합니다, 부인. 괜찮으세요?
You don't look well.
당신은 표정이 좋지 않습니다.
Yes, I'm fine. Thank you.
네, 괜찮아요. 감사합니다.
Ma'am! Are you all right?
부인! 괜찮으세요?
Hurry up and call 911!
서둘러서 911에 전화하세요!
Ma'am, are you all right?
부인, 괜찮으세요?
-Try these on. -What?
- 이것저것 입어보세요. -무엇?
-They look good. Look in the mirror. -I already know what they look like.
- 좋아 보이는군요. 거울을보세요. -나는 그들이 어떻게 생겼는지 이미 알고 있어요.
-You look like a singer. -I do.
-가수처럼 보이시네요. -그래요.
-I'll buy these for you. -No need. Forget it.
-내가 이걸 사줄게. - 필요없어요. 잊어버리세요.
Just say yes before I change my mind.
내 마음이 바뀌기 전에 그냥 그렇다고 대답해 주세요.
Honestly. I said it's fine.
솔직히. 나는 괜찮다고 말했다.
JUNG-MIN'S MOM
정민의 엄마
I'll go pay for these.
내가 가서 이것들 값을 지불할게.
Okay.
좋아요.
-Hello? -
-안녕하세요? -
What do you think? Waiting for my flight.
어떻게 생각하나요? 비행기를 기다리고 있어요.
Honey, guess where I am right now.
여보, 내가 지금 어디에 있는지 맞춰보세요.
-What? -I'm in the emergency room.
-무엇? -응급실에 있어요.
Why?
왜?
I fainted in the department store.
나는 백화점에서 기절했다.
Who did?
누가 그랬나요?
What do you mean "who"?
"누구"란 무슨 뜻입니까?
Me. Your wife.
나. 당신의 아내.
-Why did you suddenly faint? -I don't know.
-왜 갑자기 기절했나요? -모르겠습니다.
I fainted, and when I woke up, I was in the emergency room.
기절했다가 깨어났을 때, 저는 응급실에 있었습니다.
The resident here says my eyes look jaundiced,
여기 주민이 말하길 내 눈이 황달이 된 것 같아,
so they're running a liver panel.
그래서 그들은 간 패널을 운영하고 있습니다.
They just took my blood.
그들은 방금 내 피를 가져갔습니다.
-They told me to contact a guardian. -One moment.
-보호자에게 연락하라고 하더군요. - 잠시만요.
Jung-min is probably preoccupied with his internship,
정민이는 바빠지겠지 그의 인턴쉽을 통해
your mother went to a class reunion today,
네 엄마가 오늘 동창회에 가셨어.
and you're at the airport.
그리고 당신은 공항에 있어요.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
How do you feel?
기분이 어때요?
I feel a little better after resting.
쉬고 나면 기분이 조금 나아집니다.
Is your condition bad enough that I have to cancel my conference?
당신의 상태는 충분히 나쁜가요? 내가 회의를 취소해야 한다고?
The test results aren't even back yet, so you don't have to do that.
아직 검사 결과도 나오지 않았는데, 그러니 그렇게 할 필요가 없습니다.
We'll wait for the results,
결과를 기다리겠습니다,
and my mother or your mother can come.
그러면 내 어머니나 네 어머니가 오실 수 있을 거야.
Sure, okay.
물론이죠. 알겠습니다.
-Let me know when the results are out. -
- 결과가 나오면 알려주세요. -
It looks like I'm just making you worry when you're going so far away.
내가 널 걱정하게 만드는 것 같아 당신이 아주 멀리 갈 때.
No, it's fine.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
Get some rest.
좀 쉬세요.
Ma'am, I'm going to take your blood one more time.
부인, 저 갈게요 한 번 더 혈액을 채취해 보세요.
-Why? -Your levels are abnormally high.
-왜? -레벨이 비정상적으로 높습니다.
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
-Who is it? -Her name is Cha Jeong-suk.
-누구예요? -이름은 차정숙이에요.
What is this? The results are the same.
이게 뭔가요? 결과는 동일합니다.
The GOT and GPT levels both came out to over 3,000.
GOT 및 GPT 레벨 둘 다 3,000이 넘었습니다.
Jeez, it wasn't an issue with the sample.
이런, 샘플에는 문제가 없었습니다.
Ms. Cha Jeong-suk.
차정숙씨.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Normal liver panel levels come out to under 40,
정상적인 간 패널 수준 40세 이하로 나오다
but right now yours are coming out as over 3,000.
하지만 지금 당장은 네 거야 3000개가 넘게 나오네요.
Does that mean it's acute hepatitis?
급성 간염이라는 뜻인가요?
You're well aware.
당신은 잘 알고 있습니다.
Do I need to be admitted?
입학을 꼭 해야 하나요?
Yes. Have you called your guardian?
예. 보호자에게 전화하셨나요?
Do I…
내가…
really need a guardian to come?
정말로 보호자가 와야 하나요?
SEHWA WOMEN'S UNIVERSITY '70 FRESHMEN REUNION
세화여자대학교 70년대 신입생 동창회
Goodness, walking on eggshells?
맙소사, 달걀 껍질 위를 걷고 있다고요?
I'm the matriarch of the family. They should walk on eggshells around me.
저는 이 가족의 가장입니다. 그들은 내 주변의 달걀 껍질 위를 걸어야 합니다.
My daughter-in-law still prepares a lavish meal for me every morning.
며느리는 아직 준비 중 매일 아침 나를 위한 호화로운 식사.
Your daughter-in-law deserves an award for that kind of filial love.
당신의 며느리는 상을 받을 자격이 있어요 그런 효심 때문에.
No daughter-in-law is like that these days.
며느리도 없고 요즘 그렇습니다.
Smart girls know how to manage a family when they put their minds to it.
똑똑한 소녀들은 가족을 관리하는 방법을 알고 있습니다 그들이 그것에 마음을 쏟을 때.
Maybe it's because she went to medical school, but she's really clever.
아마도 그녀가 갔기 때문이겠지 의과대학인데 정말 똑똑해요.
She's great with the kids' education and managing the house.
그녀는 아이들의 교육에 훌륭합니다 그리고 집 관리.
She didn't use a tutor and taught her kids herself.
그녀는 가정교사를 이용하지 않았어 그리고 그녀의 아이들을 직접 가르쳤습니다.
And the oldest went to medical school.
그리고 큰 아이는 의과대학에 다녔습니다.
Isn't it a waste that such a capable woman only does housework?
저런 유능한 여자가 아깝지 않나 집안일만 해요?
Only a struggling household would make their doctor daughter-in-law work.
힘겨운 집안만이 만들 수 있다 의사 며느리가 일해요.
Being as well-off as we are, why send her to work?
우리만큼 잘살고, 왜 그녀를 직장에 보내나요?
When she'd only earn a small amount?
그녀가 적은 금액만 벌었을 때?
It looks like you've saved more money by not sending her off to work.
돈을 더 절약한 것 같네요 그녀를 직장에 보내지 않음으로써.
Most families spend hundreds of millions
대부분의 가족은 수억 달러를 소비합니다.
to send their kids to med school.
아이들을 의과대학에 보내기 위해.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
It's such a relief
정말 안심이네요
to not be that pretentious woman's in-law.
그 허세 부리는 여자의 시어머니가 되지 않기 위해서요.
It's the daughter-in-law I feel bad for.
기분 나쁜 며느리예요.
If I were her daughter-in-law,
내가 그 며느리라면,
I would have probably already come down with a serious illness.
아마 벌써 내려왔을 거야 심각한 질병이 있습니다.
Emergency room?
응급실?
I have a spa reservation later too.
나중에 스파 예약도 있어요.
Is it something serious?
뭔가 심각한 일인가요?
MOM
엄마
Please give me some salt too.
소금도 좀 주세요.
Mom?
엄마?
Is everything okay?
괜찮나요?
Yes. Where are you?
예. 어디세요?
I'm at the mill.
나는 공장에 있어요.
I was going to make rice cakes with mugwort.
내가 만들려고 했는데 쑥을 넣은 떡.
You like mugwort rice cakes.
쑥떡을 좋아하시네요.
Jeez, why make rice cakes? You can just buy them.
이런, 떡은 왜 만드는 걸까요? 그냥 구매하시면 됩니다.
Handmade ones are much better.
손수 만든 것이 훨씬 좋습니다.
The rice cakes in stores have spinach mixed in to make them seem green.
가게의 떡에는 시금치가 들어있어요 녹색으로 보이도록 섞습니다.
-Have you eaten? -Yes.
-식사하셨나요? -예.
But why does your voice sound so down when you said you've already eaten?
그런데 왜 목소리가 이렇게 작아지나요? 벌써 먹었다고 했을 때?
Mom, then I guess you're off today.
엄마, 그럼 오늘은 휴가이실 것 같아요.
I'm off until tomorrow.
나는 내일까지 휴가입니다.
Why? Is something wrong?
왜? 뭔가 문제가 있나요?
If you're that worried, then just go to the hospital.
그렇게 걱정된다면, 그럼 그냥 병원에 가세요.
What?
무엇?
It's fine. It's not like she's a kid.
괜찮습니다. 그녀는 어린아이가 아닌 것 같아요.
But you feel uneasy.
하지만 당신은 불안감을 느낍니다.
I have a sense of decency, you know. How could I just leave you here and go?
나는 품위가 있습니다. 내가 어떻게 당신을 여기에 남겨두고 갈 수 있겠어요?
But what if it's serious?
하지만 심각한 경우에는 어떻게 되나요?
Wouldn't it make you feel better to just go?
그게 당신을 만들지 않을까요? 그냥 가는 게 나을 것 같아?
What? No, don't worry about it.
무엇? 아니요, 걱정하지 마세요.
But you are worrying about it.
하지만 당신은 그것에 대해 걱정하고 있습니다.
Well, it's hard not to worry when someone fainted.
글쎄요, 걱정하지 않는 게 힘들죠 누군가 기절했을 때.
But it's probably not a big deal, so let's stop talking about this.
하지만 아마도 별 문제는 아닐 것입니다. 그러니 이 얘기는 그만하자.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
I was going to give it to you on the plane later at night,
너한테 주려고 했는데 늦은 밤 비행기에서
but you can just open it.
하지만 그냥 열면 돼요.
I'll help you put it on.
입힐 수 있게 도와드릴게요.
Okay, let's be on our way.
좋아요, 가죠.
Doctor, this patient says
의사 선생님, 이 환자가 그러더군요
-their neck hurts a lot, but I said… -Yes.
-목이 많이 아프다고 했는데… - 네.
Tell them they can go home.
집에 갈 수 있다고 말해주세요.
Okay, thank you.
알겠습니다. 감사합니다.
Dr. Cha Jeong-suk.
차정숙 박사님.
Yes?
예?
A TA patient came in. Can you please check her status?
TA 환자가 들어왔습니다. 그녀의 상태를 확인해 주실 수 있나요?
Okay.
좋아요.
INTERN CHA JEONG-SUK
인턴 차정석
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Are you feeling okay?
기분 괜찮아요?
No, my leg hurts so much.
아니, 다리가 너무 아파요.
If you get treated and take medication, you'll get better in no time.
치료받고 약을 먹으면 당신은 곧 나아질 것입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
If you need anything else, please let me know.
더 필요한 사항이 있으면 알려주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Gosh.
이런.
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
Ms. Cha Jeong-suk.
차정숙씨.
Your IV drip is done. I'll take it out for you.
IV 주입이 완료되었습니다. 내가 꺼내줄게
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Excuse me, where is the convenience store?
실례합니다. 편의점은 어디에 있나요?
-It is on the fifth floor. -Okay.
- 5층에 있습니다. -좋아요.
Why is the convenience store on the fifth floor?
편의점은 왜? 5층에?
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
-Does it hurt? -Yes, it hurts.
-아파요? -네, 아파요.
It'll be over soon.
곧 끝날 거예요.
Be more gentle.
좀 더 부드러워지세요.
-It hurts, gosh. -Hold on just a little longer.
- 아파요, 맙소사. -조금만 더 참으세요.
Excuse me!
실례합니다!
You shouldn't do that here. She's a minor at that!
여기서는 그렇게 하면 안 됩니다. 그 사람은 미성년자야!
Oh, my.
아, 이런.
Thank you!
감사합니다!
You're handsome!
당신은 잘 생겼어요!
She was riding a motorcycle with older kids in the neighborhood
그녀는 오토바이를 타고 있었어요 동네 큰 아이들과 함께
and got into an accident.
그리고 사고를 당했습니다.
She tried to leave, saying she had no money,
그녀는 떠나려고 했고, 그녀는 돈이 없다고 말했고,
but I insisted on treating her.
하지만 나는 그녀를 치료하겠다고 고집했습니다.
What did you think I was doing?
내가 뭘 하고 있는 줄 알았는데?
I misunderstood the situation…
제가 상황을 잘못 이해했네요...
I'm really sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
I guess you can't just walk by a patient in need.
그냥 지나갈 수는 없을 것 같아요 도움이 필요한 환자.
It was like that time when you got into the ambulance
그때도 그랬지 구급차에 탔을 때
and today too.
그리고 오늘도.
You see, I'm a decent doctor.
알다시피, 나는 괜찮은 의사입니다.
But anyway,
하지만 어쨌든,
we don't know each other well enough to say that it's nice to see you again.
우리는 서로를 충분히 알지 못한다 다시 만나서 반가웠다고 말하려고요.
What brings you to this hospital?
이 병원에 무슨 일로 오셨나요?
I was brought into the emergency room
응급실에 실려왔어
after fainting at a department store.
백화점에서 기절한 후.
Are you okay now?
이제 괜찮아요?
I'm sure I'll be okay.
나는 괜찮을 것이라고 확신합니다.
All right, I have to see outpatients now.
좋아요, 이제 외래환자를 만나야 해요.
I wish you good luck.
행운을 빕니다.
Yes, Doctor. Goodbye.
네, 박사님. 안녕히 가세요.
We run into each other often.
우리는 자주 마주친다.
I guess so.
그런 것 같아요.
I didn't realize we'd meet again like this…
나는 몰랐다 우리 이렇게 또 만나요…
We can talk about this special connection next time.
우리는 다음에 대해 이야기 할 수 있습니다 다음엔 특별한 인연으로.
Is your guardian here?
보호자가 여기 계시나요?
The thing is, my husband is just so busy…
문제는 남편이 너무 바빠서...
He should come no matter how busy he is.
아무리 바빠도 와야 해요.
The situation isn't good right now.
지금 상황은 좋지 않습니다.
Is it really bad?
정말 나쁜가요?
I know you got out of med school long ago,
나는 당신이 오래 전에 의과대학을 졸업했다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
but you must know how serious it is when liver panel results are 3,600, right?
하지만 그게 얼마나 심각한지는 알아야 해 간 패널 결과가 3,600이면 맞죠?
Your jaundice level is really high too.
당신의 황달 수준도 정말 높습니다.
If this leads to liver failure,
이것이 간부전으로 이어지는 경우,
then there's no going back.
그러면 돌아갈 수 없습니다.
Call your guardian immediately.
즉시 보호자에게 전화하세요.
NAME: CHA JEONG-SUK
이름: 차정석
Gosh, what in the world?
세상에, 도대체 무슨 일이야?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Mom.
엄마.
I just have to stay at the hospital for a couple of days and rest.
그냥 병원에 있어야 해요 며칠 동안 휴식을 취하십시오.
You don't have to worry.
걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
But you have to be admitted, no matter what?
하지만 인정을 받아야 하고, 무슨 일이 있어도?
Yes, they need to confirm that my liver panel results
예, 확인이 필요합니다 내 간 패널 결과는
and jaundice levels decrease.
황달 수치가 감소합니다.
I see. You're a doctor, so do what you think is best.
알겠어요. 당신은 의사이고, 그러니 당신이 최선이라고 생각하는 일을 하세요.
I'm not a doctor.
나는 의사가 아닙니다.
Mom, if I haven't practiced in over 20 years, then I'm not a doctor.
엄마, 제가 연습을 안 했다면 20년이 넘으면 나는 의사가 아니다.
It's like having a driver's license you never use.
운전면허 따는거랑 똑같네 당신은 절대 사용하지 않습니다.
Hey, if a baker can't sell any bread, does that mean he's not a baker?
야, 빵집 주인이 빵 하나도 못 팔면, 그렇다면 그 사람은 제빵사가 아니라는 뜻인가요?
How is that the same thing?
어쩜 똑같은 거야?
But your husband is a doctor at a university hospital.
그런데 당신 남편은 의사예요. 대학병원에서.
Why are you staying here?
왜 여기에 머물고 있습니까?
He went to a conference in Europe today.
그는 오늘 유럽에서 열리는 회의에 참석했습니다.
Jung-min is an intern.
정민은 인턴이다.
If I ask him to make time for me, it'll put him in a tight spot.
내가 그에게 시간을 내달라고 요청하면, 그것은 그를 곤경에 빠뜨릴 것입니다.
If I stay at the hospital,
병원에 계속 있으면
I won't be able to go home for a couple of days.
집에 못 갈 것 같아 며칠 동안.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
They need me there since it'll be I-rang's midterms soon,
거기엔 내가 필요해 이제 곧 아이랑 중간고사니까
and Jung-min needs to prepare for his resident exam.
그리고 정민이도 준비해야 해 그의 주민 시험을 위해.
This is bad. There's no one to prepare food for the kids.
이것은 나쁘다. 아무도 없어요 아이들을 위한 음식을 준비하기 위해.
They aren't babies.
그들은 아기가 아닙니다.
Studying is up to them, and they can feed themselves.
공부는 그 사람의 몫이고, 그리고 그들은 스스로 먹을 수 있습니다.
Ever since you were a third grader, you made your own food and studied alone
네가 3학년 때부터, 넌 음식도 직접 만들고 혼자 공부도 했어
and still managed to get good grades.
그래도 좋은 성적을 받을 수 있었어요.
Gosh, Mom. That was ages ago.
이런, 엄마. 오래 전 일이었습니다.
The times are different, Mom.
시대는 다릅니다, 엄마.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
where did you get that medicine you gave me?
어디서 얻었어? 네가 나한테 준 그 약?
From the medicine shop at the market--
시장의 약가게에서--
Why?
왜?
Was that the issue?
그게 문제였나요?
Yes, it seems like it.
네, 그럴 것 같습니다.
Sometimes if you eat something that doesn't sit well with you,
가끔 뭔가를 먹으면 그건 너랑 잘 안 맞는 것 같아
it can result in acute hepatitis.
급성 간염이 발생할 수 있습니다.
These terrible hacks.
이 끔찍한 해킹.
How dare they mess around with something like that?
감히 저들이 어떻게 장난을 쳐요? 그런걸로?
I should've taken you to a proper Korean medical clinic
널 데려갔어야 했는데 제대로된 한의원으로
to have the medicine made for you.
당신을 위해 약을 만들어 달라고 하세요.
I just trusted that medicine shop because I heard they were good.
난 그냥 그 약가게를 믿었을 뿐이야 왜냐면 그 사람들이 좋다고 들었거든요.
I must've lost my mind.
내가 정신을 잃은 게 틀림없어.
Don't blame yourself.
자신을 비난하지 마십시오.
I'll be back on my feet in a few days.
나는 며칠 안에 다시 일어설 것이다.
Don't go there and take out your anger on them.
거기 가지 마세요 그리고 그들에게 당신의 분노를 거두십시오.
-You're really going to get better, right? -Gosh, of course.
-정말 나아지겠죠? -물론이지.
It's not a big deal.
그것은 큰 문제가 아니다.
It's okay, Ms. Oh.
괜찮아요, 오 선생님.
1 DAY LATER
1일 후
SEOMYEONG UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
서면대학교병원
30 DAYS LATER
30일 후
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-Please sit over here. -Sit here.
- 여기 앉으세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
The donor compatibility results for a liver transplant came out.
기증자 호환성 결과 간 이식이 나왔습니다.
Your son's blood type doesn't match, your daughter is still a minor,
아들의 혈액형이 일치하지 않습니다. 당신 딸은 아직 미성년자예요.
and your mother and mother-in-law are elderly.
그리고 네 엄마 그리고 시어머니는 나이가 많으세요.
But thankfully, the results of your husband's test look good.
하지만 다행히도 결과는 남편의 시험 결과가 좋아 보이는군요.
He has taken great care of his body, so he doesn't have a fatty liver.
그는 자신의 몸을 매우 잘 관리했고, 그래서 그는 지방간이 없습니다.
Goodness. Thank you, Doctor.
선량. 고마워요, 박사님.
The most important thing is your husband's consent as the donor.
가장 중요한 것 기증자로서 남편의 동의입니다.
Are you saying my son has to give his liver to her?
내 아들 말하는 거야? 그의 간을 그녀에게 주어야 하나요?
I'm not saying that he must. I'm just saying that it is possible.
나는 그가 그래야 한다고 말하는 것이 아닙니다. 나는 단지 그것이 가능하다고 말하고 있는 것이다.
That can't happen.
그런 일은 일어날 수 없습니다.
Cutting open a perfectly healthy person to give away part of his liver?
완벽하게 건강한 사람을 자르다 간 일부를 기증하려고?
He can't take the risk of going under the knife.
그 사람은 위험을 감수할 수가 없어 칼 아래로 들어가는 것.
Please don't recommend that surgery to my son.
추천하지 마세요 내 아들의 그 수술.
-I'll never allow it. -Mother.
- 절대 허락하지 않을 거예요. -어머니.
Please stop.
그만하세요.
Stop what?
뭘 멈춰?
Even if you say yes, I'm against it.
그렇다고 해도 저는 반대입니다.
Get out of the way.
비켜가세요.
Jeong-suk, it's not like you're on the brink of death,
정숙아, 그렇지 않아 당신은 죽음의 문턱에 있습니다.
so let's just wait for a brain-dead donor, okay?
그러니 그냥 기다리자 뇌사 기증자를 위한 거죠, 그렇죠?
Gosh, my head. I'm so dizzy.
이런, 내 머리. 너무 어지러워요.
-Grandma. -Mother!
-할머니. -어머니!
-Mother, are you all right? -Why do I feel like this?
-엄마, 괜찮아요? - 나는 왜 이런 기분이 들까?
Come this way.
이쪽으로 오세요.
-Here, sit here.
- 여기, 여기 앉아요.
-Careful. -What's wrong with me?
-주의 깊은. - 나한테 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요?
-Look at me, Mother. -I think I'm going to throw up.
- 저를 보세요, 어머니. - 토할 것 같아요.
Can you see me? Are you going to throw up?
나를 볼 수 있나요? 토할 건가요?
Are you okay? How sick do you feel, Mother?
괜찮으세요? 엄마, 몸이 얼마나 아프세요?
No, wait.
아니, 잠깐만요.
-Hold on. -My gosh.
-기다리다. -맙소사.
You don't have a fever. Mother, look at me.
당신은 열이 없습니다. 어머니, 저를 보세요.
Ms. Kwak. Are you awake?
곽씨. 깨어있나요?
Please open your eyes.
눈을 떠주세요.
Just keep your eyes closed then.
그럼 그냥 눈을 감고 계세요.
Of course, I understand how a mother would feel
물론 이해해요 엄마는 어떤 기분이실까
at the thought of their perfectly healthy child going under the knife.
그들의 완벽함을 생각하면 칼 아래로 들어가는 건강한 아이.
But no matter how bad you felt,
하지만 아무리 기분이 나빠도,
you shouldn't have said those things in front of a person that's sick.
넌 그런 말을 하지 말았어야 했어 아픈 사람 앞에서.
If it was In-ho that was sick,
아픈 사람이 인호라면,
my daughter would've given him all her organs.
내 딸이 그에게 줬을 텐데 그녀의 모든 장기.
Ms. Oh! Talking in hypotheticals is wrong.
오 씨! 가정적으로 말하는 것은 잘못된 것입니다.
Right now, the healthy person
지금 건강한 사람은
that has to give up their liver is my son, not that daughter of yours.
간을 포기해야 하는 사람은 내 아들이다. 네 딸이 아니야.
The word "if" doesn't fit this situation.
'if'라는 단어는 이 상황에 맞지 않습니다.
Did you just say "that daughter of yours"?
방금 "당신의 딸"이라고 말했나요?
When things were good, she was your daughter-in-law,
상황이 좋았던 시절, 그 사람은 당신의 며느리였어요.
but now she's "that daughter of yours"?
그런데 지금 그 사람이 "네 딸"이야?
Don't change the subject like that.
그런 식으로 주제를 바꾸지 마세요.
To be honest, aren't you the person to blame for all this?
솔직히 말해서 그렇지 않나요? 이 모든 일에 책임이 있는 사람은 누구입니까?
It's all because of that cheap medicine!
이게 다 그 싸구려 약 때문이야!
And while we're on the topic, Jung-min got into that car accident
그리고 우리가 주제에 대해 이야기하는 동안 정민이 교통사고를 당했어요
while you were watching him when he was seven.
당신이 그를 지켜보는 동안 그가 일곱 살이었을 때.
This whole time, you've been going on about how Jeong-suk quit her practice.
그동안 넌 계속 그랬어 정숙이가 어떻게 연습을 그만뒀는지에 대해서.
But don't feel upset about her giving up her practice.
하지만 속상해하지 마세요 그녀가 연습을 포기한 것에 대해.
Frankly speaking,
솔직히 말해서,
it's that accident that made her a full-time housewife.
그녀를 만든 건 바로 그 사고야 전업주부.
Gosh, I'm so furious.
이런, 정말 화가 나네요.
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
You were more injured than Jung-min was back then.
니가 더 다쳤어 그때 정민보다.
You still have that herniated disc in your back from that accident.
아직도 디스크 탈출증이 있으신가요? 그 사고로 인해 허리를 굽혔어요.
How could she talk about that accident like that?
그녀는 어떻게 말을 할 수 있었나요? 그 사고에 대해 그런 식으로요?
I don't care whether your mother-in-law thinks like that or not.
네 시어머니가 있든 없든 상관없어 그렇게 생각하든 말든.
Rather than that, I feel like In-ho is just so cold-hearted.
그보다는, 인호가 너무 냉정한 것 같아요.
It always made me uncomfortable that my son-in-law was so cold and fussy.
항상 나를 불편하게 만들었어 내 사위는 너무 차갑고 까다로웠어요.
But given his upbringing, I just accepted it.
그러나 그의 성장과정을 볼 때, 그냥 받아들였어요.
But when his own mother talked like that in front of the kids,
하지만 그의 어머니가 아이들 앞에서 그런 얘기를 했는데,
he barely did anything to stop her.
그는 그녀를 막기 위해 거의 아무것도 하지 않았습니다.
His wife is in this condition, and even if it was just empty words,
그의 아내가 이런 상태인데, 그저 빈말이라 할지라도
he didn't even say he'd go through with the surgery.
그 사람은 말하지도 않았어 그는 수술을 받게 될 것입니다.
Even if we're family,
우리가 가족이라 해도
going under the knife isn't easy, Mom.
칼 밑으로 들어가는 건 쉽지 않아요, 엄마.
In this day and age,
이 시대에,
someone as educated and smart as you
당신만큼 교육받고 똑똑한 사람
spent your entire youth taking care of your ailing father-in-law
청춘을 다 보냈다 아픈 시아버지를 돌보다
and putting up with your mother-in-law.
그리고 시어머니를 참으세요.
So how could they do this to you?
그러면 그들이 어떻게 당신에게 이런 짓을 할 수 있겠습니까?
Mom.
엄마.
Mom, look at me.
엄마, 저 좀 보세요.
Mom, don't beg.
엄마, 구걸하지 마세요.
Then who will?
그러면 누가 할 것인가?
Who will beg for your life?
누가 당신의 생명을 구걸하겠습니까?
Risking her life for her child is what a mother does.
아이를 위해 목숨을 걸고 엄마가 하는 일이에요.
So begging for your life is nothing.
그러므로 목숨을 구걸하는 것은 아무것도 아닙니다.
If you can just live, I'd get down on my knees and beg.
살 수만 있다면, 무릎을 꿇고 빌고 싶습니다.
Mom.
엄마.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'm sorry, Mom.
미안해요, 엄마.
What is this mess? Why on earth are you doing this?
이 혼란은 무엇입니까? 도대체 왜 이러는 걸까요?
You bunch of hacks.
당신은 해킹 무리입니다.
How could you trick people by using such lousy ingredients?
어떻게 사람을 속일 수 있니? 이렇게 형편없는 재료를 사용해서?
My daughter ate this garbage, and now she might die.
딸아이가 이 쓰레기를 먹었어요 이제 그녀는 죽을 수도 있습니다.
-What are you going to do about that? -My goodness, these are expensive!
-그건 어떻게 할 겁니까? -맙소사, 이거 비싸요!
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
Can't you just use your words?
그냥 말 좀 쓰면 안 돼?
Jong-su,
종수,
you're the best candidate for the surgery.
당신은 수술에 가장 적합한 후보자입니다.
But her husband can do it.
하지만 남편은 할 수 있어요.
So why are you doing this to me?
그럼 나한테 왜 이러는 걸까요?
I wouldn't be asking you a favor like this if I wasn't this desperate.
내가 너한테 이런 부탁은 안 할 텐데. 내가 이렇게 절망적이지 않았다면.
Here. Take this.
여기. 이것을 가져가세요.
This is everything I have.
이것이 내가 가진 전부입니다.
It's not a small amount.
적은 금액이 아닙니다.
I'll give all of this to you. Just please save my daughter.
이 모든 것을 당신에게 드리겠습니다. 제발 내 딸을 구해주세요.
When my mother died young, I will never forget how you took us in
어머니가 어렸을 때 돌아가셨을 때, 나는 당신이 우리를 어떻게 받아들이는지 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다
and raised us as if we were your children.
그리고 우리를 당신의 자녀처럼 키우셨습니다.
And the fact I can live as a proper adult like this is all thanks to you.
그리고 제대로된 어른으로 살아갈 수 있다는 사실 이게 다 네 덕분이야.
But you doing this
그런데 당신은 이런 일을 하고 있어요
feels like you're pressuring me to pay back the debt.
당신이 나에게 압력을 가하는 것 같아요 빚을 갚으려고.
It's agonizing.
괴로워요.
Jong-su, you're the only one I can cling to.
종수야 너뿐이야 나는 매달릴 수 있다.
I heard Professor Seo's wife's condition is pretty serious.
서 교수 부인의 상태를 들었습니다. 꽤 심각합니다.
I mean, how did he let it get to that point?
내 말은, 그 사람이 어떻게 그렇게 놔뒀단 말이에요? 그 지점까지 가?
I heard Professor Seo was a match.
서 교수가 일치한다고 들었습니다.
I know, right?
나도 알아, 그렇지?
It's going to be hard if they still can't find a donor.
힘들겠다 아직도 기증자를 찾을 수 없다면요.
Professor Seo was in the same class as you in medical school, right?
서 교수는 같은 수업을 들었다. 당신이 의과대학에 다니듯이요, 그렇죠?
-Yes, he was. -Then do you know his wife too?
-네, 그랬어요. -그럼 그의 아내도 아시나요?
I don't. I wasn't close with Professor Seo back then.
나는 아니에요. 나는 가까이 있지 않았다 그때 서교수님이랑.
But why is he having his wife
그런데 그 사람은 왜 아내를 갖고 있는 걸까요?
treated at a different hospital and not this one?
다른 병원에서 치료 받음 그리고 이건 아니야?
His wife said being at this hospital would be uncomfortable.
그의 아내가 이 병원에 있다고 하더군요 불편할 것입니다.
His son is an intern here.
그의 아들은 이곳에서 인턴으로 일하고 있습니다.
Professor Seo must be all out of sorts right now.
서 교수님은 꼭 지금은 모든 게 이상해요.
-That's what I heard. -It must be so nice for you.
- 나도 그렇게 들었어. - 정말 좋을 것 같아요.
-We should eat something delicious. -What do you want to eat for lunch?
- 우리 맛있는 거 먹어야지. -점심으로 무엇을 먹고 싶나요?
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
Patient Kim Yeon-suk from Ward 151…
151병동 김연숙 환자…
-Doctor. -What are you doing here?
-박사님. - 여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
Just observing people.
그냥 사람들을 관찰하는 거죠.
When you're at a hospital, you see all kinds of things.
병원에 있을 때, 당신은 모든 종류의 것을 봅니다.
There are more cases than you think of donors suddenly changing their minds.
생각보다 경우가 많네요 기부자들이 갑자기 마음을 바꿨습니다.
It isn't an easy decision to donate your organ,
쉬운 결정은 아니죠 당신의 장기를 기증하기 위해,
even if it's to your family.
그것이 가족을 위해서라 할지라도.
I just feel so bad…
그냥 기분이 너무 나빠서…
putting this pressure on my family.
우리 가족에게 이런 압력을 가하고 있어요.
Even if something happens to me,
나에게 무슨 일이 일어나도
I hope they don't live their lives feeling guilty.
그 사람들은 안 살았으면 좋겠어 죄책감을 느끼는 그들의 삶.
Don't think about that.
그것에 대해 생각하지 마십시오.
Just get better.
그냥 나아지세요.
When I was an intern,
제가 인턴이었을 때,
I saw mothers who were just in their early thirties
엄마들을 봤어요 막 30대 초반이었던 그 사람
develop cancer and die several times.
암에 걸리고 여러 번 죽습니다.
Maybe it's because of that, but once I reached my forties,
어쩌면 그것 때문일지도 모르지만, 그런데 마흔이 되고 나니
I thought even if I came down with a terminal illness,
내려와도 생각했어 불치병으로,
there wouldn't be anything to be bitter about.
아무것도 없을 텐데 씁쓸하다.
Even though I always worried that
늘 걱정했는데도
something terrible might happen to my husband or kids if I was gone,
끔찍한 일이 일어날지도 몰라 내가 없으면 남편이나 아이들에게,
I would have those kinds of thoughts from time to time.
그런 종류가 있었을 텐데 가끔씩 생각이 납니다.
Doctor, I'm so jealous of you.
박사님, 정말 부럽습니다.
When I was an intern, I wanted to become a surgeon.
제가 인턴이었을 때, 나는 외과 의사가되고 싶었습니다.
When I was doing my training,
제가 훈련을 하던 시절,
the first surgery I observed was a liver transplant.
첫 번째 수술 나는 간 이식을 관찰했습니다.
I had no idea I'd end up needing to receive one.
내가 끝날 줄은 몰랐어 하나를 받아야합니다.
Now that I think about it,
지금 생각해보면,
I really miss the operating room.
수술실이 정말 그리워요.
Then…
그럼…
would you like to visit one?
한 번 가보고 싶나요?
INTENSIVE CARE UNIT PEDIATRIC OPERATING ROOM
집중 치료실 소아 수술실
Doctor.
의사.
A photo to commemorate the event.
행사 기념 사진입니다.
You should take a selfie in those clothes.
그 옷을 입고 셀카를 찍어야 해요.
Gosh, no.
이런, 아니.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Doctor, but isn't this not allowed?
박사님, 그러면 안되는 거 아닌가요?
Just for today, you're a colleague who has come to observe a surgery.
오늘만은 동료야 수술을 참관하러 오신 분.
A colleague?
동료?
Yes, you have a medical license, don't you?
예, 그렇습니다. 의사 면허증, 그렇지 않나요?
-I do. -Then you're a colleague.
-그래요. -그럼 동료군요.
It's a 40-year-old man suffering from Crohn's disease.
40세 남자입니다 크론병을 앓고 있다.
He has an intestinal obstruction and an abscess,
그 사람은 장폐색이 있어서 그리고 농양,
so we will be performing a bowel resection surgery.
그래서 우리는 공연할 거야 대장 절제 수술.
Scalpel.
메스.
-Do I have to feel guilty? -Why?
-죄책감을 느껴야 하나요? -왜?
You went on a trip with me on the day your wife went to the ER.
당신은 나와 함께 여행을 떠났어요 당신 아내가 응급실에 갔던 날.
It would've happened even if I had gone to the hospital.
그런 일이 있었을 텐데 병원에 갔음에도 불구하고.
But it's a relief that a donor was found.
그런데 기증자를 찾았다니 다행이네요.
Her cousin, right?
그 사촌 맞죠?
Yes.
예.
It's times like this that I envy your wife.
이럴때가 있구나 당신 아내가 부러워요.
When I'm sick, will you be able to stay by my side?
내가 아플 때, 내 옆에 있어줄 수 있겠니?
Will I die all alone in my later years?
나중에는 혼자 죽게 될까요?
-I think about these things. -Choi Seung-hi.
- 이런 생각이 듭니다. - 최승희.
Sometimes I have to nag like this so I can relieve my stress too.
가끔은 이렇게 잔소리도 해야지 그래서 스트레스도 풀 수 있어요.
The three of us have a maze-like complicated relationship.
우리 셋은 미로 같은 복잡한 관계.
There are no answers and there is no end.
답도 없고 끝도 없습니다.
I have nothing I can say to you.
나는 당신에게 말할 수 있는 것이 없습니다.
I don't know if there will ever be answers or an end,
앞으로도 그럴지는 모르겠지만 대답이 되거나 끝이 되거나
but I can promise you this.
하지만 이건 약속할 수 있어요.
I won't leave you to be all alone.
나는 당신을 혼자 두지 않을 것입니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Where is Jong-su?
종수는 어디 있어요?
I'm sorry, Ms. Oh.
죄송해요, 오 선생님.
What do you mean, sorry?
미안하다니 무슨 말이야?
EMERGENCY BELL
비상벨
We can't accept this.
우리는 이것을 받아들일 수 없습니다.
Ms. Oh, I don't want him to get the surgery either.
오 씨, 난 그 사람을 원하지 않아요 수술을 받으러 가거나.
Our child is still so young, and I'm scared.
우리 아이는 아직 어리지만, 그리고 나는 무서워요.
He couldn't bring himself to tell you, so I came here to tell you instead.
그 사람은 차마 너에게 말할 수가 없었어 그래서 내가 대신 말하려고 여기 왔어요.
But the surgery is booked for tomorrow.
그런데 내일 수술이 예약되어 있어요.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Cold blue. Room 306, code blue.
차가운 파란색. 306호, 코드 블루.
-Ma'am, you can't go in right now. -That's my daughter…
- 부인, 지금은 들어가실 수 없습니다. -저 사람은 내 딸인데…
My daughter suddenly slipped into a coma
딸이 갑자기 혼수상태에 빠졌어요
and went into the intensive care unit.
그리고 중환자실로 들어갔습니다.
I can't even see her face for a moment?
잠시도 그 사람 얼굴이 안보이는데?
She's in a critical state right now, so you can't visit her.
그녀는 지금 위독한 상태에 있습니다. 그래서 당신은 그녀를 방문할 수 없습니다.
Jeong-suk…
정숙…
-Mom.
-엄마.
Mom, are you okay?
엄마, 괜찮아요?
Mom.
엄마.
Dad.
아빠.
Can't you just donate your liver?
그냥 간을 기증하면 안 되나요?
It's not that simple.
그렇게 간단하지 않습니다.
This is a much more dangerous surgery than you think…
훨씬 더 위험한 수술이다 생각보다…
As long as it's fine with you,
당신만 괜찮다면,
I also think it'd be great if you could donate your liver.
저도 참 좋을 것 같아요 간을 기증할 수 있다면.
There's no other alternative, Father.
다른 대안은 없어요, 신부님.
Mother, I think I have to go through with the surgery.
어머니, 제 생각엔 그런 것 같아요 수술을 진행하려고 합니다.
We have to save the children's mother.
우리는 아이들의 엄마를 구해야 합니다.
Her condition is too critical to wait for a donor.
그녀의 상태는 너무 심각하다 기증자를 기다리기 위해.
Please give me permission, Mother!
허락해주세요, 어머니!
If I don't give you permission, will you not do the surgery?
내가 허락하지 않으면, 수술 안 할 거야?
Get up.
일어나세요.
Why are you on your knees?
왜 무릎을 꿇고 있습니까?
You did nothing wrong.
당신은 아무 잘못도 하지 않았습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
This is why I told you not to get into a marriage like this.
이것이 내가 당신에게 말한 이유입니다. 이런 결혼은 하지 말라고.
I was against it from the get-go.
나는 처음부터 반대했다.
How could someone so smart be so daft at the same time?
어떻게 그렇게 똑똑한 사람이 있을 수 있지? 동시에 너무 멍청해?
To leave that perfect girl, Seung-hi…
완벽한 그녀를 떠나기 위해 승희..
I never forgot her name because it was such a waste.
나는 그녀의 이름을 결코 잊지 않았다 너무 낭비였으니까요.
You kicked your own luck away like that
넌 그렇게 자신의 행운을 걷어차버렸어
and got a good-for-nothing girl pregnant.
그리고 쓸모없는 여자를 임신하게 했어요.
Gosh, men are unbelievable.
맙소사, 남자들은 믿을 수가 없어요.
Get out, you bastard.
나가, 이 개자식아.
Get out!
나가세요!
-Get out! -I'm leaving.
-나가세요! -나는 떠난다.
I'm so furious. Gosh…
나는 너무 화가 난다. 이런…
Goodness! Filthy little bastards!
맙소사! 더러운 새끼들아!
SEOMYEONG UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
서면대학교병원
In-ho,
인호,
thank you for making such a difficult decision.
만들어주셔서 감사합니다 정말 어려운 결정이군요.
I'll never forget this.
나는 이것을 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다.
No. I…
아뇨. 저는…
should've said yes from the beginning. I'm sorry.
그렇다고 말했어야 했는데 처음부터. 죄송합니다.
Gosh, don't say that.
이런, 그런 말 하지 마세요.
It isn't easy to decide to donate your liver to someone.
결정하기가 쉽지 않네요 당신의 간을 누군가에게 기증하는 것.
Let me go get some water.
물 좀 가지러 갈게요.
Honey.
꿀.
I know you made a difficult decision.
당신이 어려운 결정을 내렸다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
This might just be an excuse, but if I think of Mom and the kids,
이건 그냥 핑계일 수도 있지만 하지만 엄마와 아이들을 생각하면
I want to live a little bit longer.
나는 조금 더 오래 살고 싶다.
It'd be a lie to say there has never been a time when I hated you.
있었다고 하면 거짓말이겠죠 내가 당신을 미워한 적은 한 번도 없었습니다.
Every time you made me think
네가 나에게 생각을 하게 만들 때마다
that you'd be okay whether or not I was here,
당신은 괜찮을 거라고 내가 여기 있었든 아니든,
I wanted to confirm that wasn't true.
나는 그것이 사실이 아니라는 것을 확인하고 싶었다.
And it made me become even more engrossed in household work.
그것이 나를 이렇게 만들었습니다 집안일에 더욱 열중하게 되었습니다.
But still, there was a part of me that held feelings of hate
하지만 그래도 내 일부가 있었어 증오의 감정을 품고 있던
and resentment toward you.
그리고 당신을 향한 원망.
But after falling ill like this…
그런데 이렇게 아프고 나니…
it turns out my husband is the one who will save my life.
내 남편이 밝혀졌어 내 생명을 구해줄 사람은 바로 이 사람이다.
I'll never stop being grateful to you for the rest of my life.
나는 당신에게 감사하는 것을 결코 멈추지 않을 것입니다 내 남은 생애 동안.
I mean it.
진심이에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
And…
그리고…
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
-Is this really the only option? -It is.
-이게 정말 유일한 선택인가요? -그것은.
Will you donate your liver to me too if I get sick?
당신도 나에게 간을 기증하시겠습니까? 내가 아프면?
I will.
그럴게요.
Then give me your liver, your kidney, and your heart!
그러면 간을 주세요. 당신의 신장과 심장!
Give me everything!
나에게 모든 것을 줘!
All of it!
전부!
Then I'll die.
그러면 나는 죽을 것이다.
-Seung-hi. -What?
-승희. -무엇?
I'll call you when the surgery is over.
수술 끝나면 전화할게요.
Until then, be brave and well, just like you always are.
그때까지 힘내시고 건강하세요. 언제나 그렇듯.
Actually…
사실…
I went to Gusan University School of Medicine in 1995.
구산대학교에 다녔어요 1995년 의과대학.
May I ask which university you went to?
어느 대학에 다녔는지 물어봐도 될까요?
I was raised in the US. I did my undergrad at Stanford
저는 미국에서 자랐습니다. 저는 스탠포드에서 학부를 했어요
and then went to Harvard Medical School.
그리고 하버드 의과대학에 진학했습니다.
Well, I've heard all the rumors about what a talented doctor you are,
글쎄, 소문은 다 들었어 당신이 얼마나 재능 있는 의사인지에 대해
but as a fellow surgeon,
하지만 동료 외과의사로서
I need to be able to continue to perform long surgeries, don't you think?
계속해서 공연을 할 수 있어야 해요 수술이 길지 않나요?
If there are any aftereffects I should be aware of,
후유증이 있는 경우 알아두어야 하는데,
please tell me everything honestly.
모든 것을 솔직하게 말해주세요.
Not to your wife, but to you?
아내가 아니라 당신에게요?
Yes.
예.
You'll have a scar.
흉터가 생길 겁니다.
A scar?
흉터?
Yes.
예.
You could suffer from jaundice or a high fever,
황달로 고생할 수도 있어요 아니면 고열이 나거나
but if you take good care of yourself,
하지만 자신을 잘 돌보면
there's nothing to worry about.
걱정할 것이 없습니다.
I'm not sitting here to hear obvious answers.
난 여기 앉아 있지 않아 분명한 답변을 듣기 위해.
Could you let me know how many liver transplants
나에게 알려주시겠어요? 간 이식 횟수
you've performed and their success rate?
당신이 수행한 성과와 성공률은?
-Mr. Seo. -Yes?
-씨. 서. -예?
You're a surgeon,
당신은 외과 의사입니다.
so I'm sure you know the surgery process and the aftereffects.
그러니 당신도 알고 있을 거라 확신해요 수술과정과 후유증.
But if you find yourself hesitating about the surgery,
하지만 자신을 발견한다면 수술을 망설이시거나,
you can give it more thought before deciding.
좀 더 생각해봐도 돼 결정하기 전에.
That's not what I meant.
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어.
SURGERY, ANESTHESIA, BLOOD TRANSFUSION CONSENT FORM
수술, 마취, 수혈 동의서
CONSENTING PARTY'S SIGNATURE OR SEAL
동의 당사자의 서명 또는 인감
I'm getting a call.
전화를 받고 있어요.
INCOMING CALL CHOI SEUNG-HI
수신 전화 최승희
In-ho.
인호.
In-ho, don't do it!
인호야, 그러지 마!
You absolutely can't!
당신은 절대로 할 수 없습니다!
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
OPERATING ROOM 1
수술실 1
PATIENT NAME: CHA JEONG-SUK SURGEON: ROY KIM
환자 이름 : 차정석 외과의사: 로이킴
We will now begin Cha Jeong-suk's liver transplant.
이제 시작하겠습니다 차정숙 간이식.
Scalpel.
메스.
In-ho, don't do it!
인호야, 그러지 마!
Don't sign it!
서명하지 마세요!
No! You absolutely can't!
아니요! 당신은 절대로 할 수 없습니다!
No, I won't let you!
아니, 허락하지 않을 거야!
Mom, are you okay?
엄마, 괜찮아요?
Mom.
엄마.
-Honey. -Yes?
-꿀. -예?
Yes, tell me. What is it?
예, 말해 보세요. 그것은 무엇입니까?
What?
무엇?
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
You…
당신은…
little…
조금…
bastard.
개자식.
Excuse me, the patient here has woken up!
죄송합니다. 여기 환자가 깨어났습니다!
DOCTOR CHA
차 박사
After coming back from the brink of death, it turns out all of that was meaningless.
죽음의 문턱에서 돌아온 후, 그 모든 것이 무의미한 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
Has she lost her mind?
그녀는 정신을 잃었나요?
You said I didn't have to worry about the household chores anymore.
걱정할 필요가 없다고 하더군요 더 이상 집안일에 대해 이야기하지 마세요.
-Is my juice not ready yet? -You can make it yourself.
-주스가 아직 준비되지 않았나요? -직접 만들어도 됩니다.
Maybe it's because I escaped death.
아마도 내가 죽음을 면했기 때문일 것이다.
I wanted to start doing things I hadn't done before.
일을 시작하고 싶었습니다. 이전에는 해본 적이 없었습니다.
Did the big surgery mess with her head or something?
큰 수술을 했나요? 머리를 엉망으로 만든 걸까요?
Why are you suddenly acting weird?
갑자기 왜 이상한 짓을 하는 거야?
I spent the last 20 years not doing stuff like this.
저는 지난 20년을 보냈습니다. 이런 일은 하지 마세요.
I'm going to live however I please from now on.
나는 살 것이다 하지만 지금부터 부탁드리겠습니다.
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-ji Chi
자막번역 : 지윤지